there are multiple rewards
of making the right choice when you
plant a seed
not only does it mature into a fruit
bearing tree
but also provides you with cool shade a
ulip
or unit-linked insurance plan works in a
similar manner
it combines the fruits of savings along
with the protection of insurance
with a single plan so how does a ulip
work
a ulip offers a life insurance cover
that protects the financial
future of your loved ones in your
absence
at the same time your corpus is invested
in market-linked securities
giving you the potential to grow your
wealth
on surviving the policy term you will
get your fund value at maturity
you can choose to withdraw the maturity
amount as a lump sum
to fulfill life goals such as purchasing
a house
or use structured payout using
settlement option
to finance critical milestones like
paying for your child's education
or generating retirement income ulips
also give you the option of partial
withdrawal before maturity
this can help in case of an emergency
like an urgent medical treatment
so how do you choose the best ulip look
for a ulip with low charges
which includes mortality charge premium
allocation charges
fund management charges and
administrative charges
one that offers investment flexibility
such as fund switches
premium direction and top-up options as
well as loyalty benefits
such as additional complimentary units
awarded for lumps and premium payment
or long-term investing it is important
that ulip
offers multiple investment strategies
such as life cycle based investing
or an automatic transfer strategy that
helps align your investments with your
financial goals
once you've found the right eulip for
you select the investment amount based
on your goal and budget
and choose a premium payment frequency
that suits your pocket
the earlier you invest in a ulip the
sooner you will reach your financial
goals
reap the benefits of smart investing
while ensuring your loved ones are taken
care of
even in your absence
you